A Guide to the Hunter-Garnett Families Papers, 1806-1889
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Hunter-Garnett Families Papers 1806-1889
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
38-45-c
This collection consists of over 700 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Scope and Content Information
Papers of the Hunter-Garnett families consist primarily of personal, financial, and political correspondence of Muscoe Garnett. Correspondence of Garnett and related family members discusses local, state and national politics; student life and administrative concerns at the University of Virginia; Rio de Janeiro, 1856-1858; family life at "Elmwood"; travel on the continent, 1869-1873; and business affairs.
Of interest among many topics are the Compromise of 1850; states' rights politics in the 1850s, opposition to Andrew Jackson's administration; engineering work for the New York and Erie Rail Road; the cruise of the U.S.S. Cyane, 1842-1844; Indian burial grounds; 1790s [?]and 1830s slave swaps and other news of family servants including hires, illnesses and death; St. Mary's College, Baltimore, 1811; and Reconstruction.
In addition there are architectural plans, plats, and legal documents re the "Elmwood" estate; daybooks; ante-bellum political speeches and broadsides; school papers; artistic sketches; scrapbooks; debating society minutes and journals; business and legal papers; genealogical papers; papers regarding American Red Cross work in France during World War I; and a journal of travel in Portugal, 1807.
Contents List
- Correspondence
  - William Baynham (1749-1814) to William S. Wyatt
    - 1813 Oct 23 (Box 1)
      [offering congratulations on his marriage and reminding him of a proverb "a man cannot wive and thrive in the same year"]
    - 1814 Jan 9 (Box 1)
      [extending an invitation to visit, discussing family illness including his own]
  - Henry Laurens Brooke to Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett
    - 1845 Dec 10 (Box 1)
      [a legal claim of Garnett's; Virginia politics and William "Extra Billy" Smith (1797-1887)]
  - James Lawrence Cabell (1813-1889) to Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett
    - 1856 Feb 14 (Box 1)
      [University of Virginia, concerning a memorial dedicated to his late uncle, Joseph Carrington Cabell (1778-1856), Rector of the University; mentioning William Joseph Robertson (1817-1898); and discussing the merits of John Staige Davis (1824-1885) and the importance of keeping him at the University. Cabell and Garnett were on the University's Board of Visitors.]
  - Jabez Lamar Monroe Curry (1825-1903) to Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett
    - 1853 Feb 10 (Box 1)
      [Alabama legislator, discussing that state's public attention on "the necessity of some superior facilities for general education" and requesting Garnett's opinions on education and the "common-school-system"]
  - George Mifflin Dallas (1792-1864) to Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett
    - 1851 July 5 (Box 1)
      [discussing at length his opinions on the compromise resolutions, the importance of having "the Constitution restore to its integrity..."]
  - Philip Pendleton Dandridge to Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett
    - 1850 Oct 23 (Box 1)
      [Garnett's pamphlet "The Union...," state politics and personal]
  - Charles Dickens (1812-1870) to Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett
    - 1842 Feb 16 (Box 1)
      [declining an "invitation to a Public entertainment," discussing his desire to see as much as possible of this country and making himself acquainted with the people and institutions, and expressing his hope to see Garnett during his visit to Virginia]
  - Charles Ellet, Jr. (1810-1862) to Charles Fenton Mercer Garnett
    - 1834 Apr 10 (Box 1)
      [the gathering of [Northern and Southern] opponents of the Andrew Jackson administration, assembling on the steps of the Masonic Hall, and detailing events of the day and Friday's confrontation]
    - 1834 Apr 18 (Box 1)
      [in reference to an inquiry of Garnett's, mentioning his plan of the Potomac Bridge sent before Congress]
    - 1834 June 21 (Box 1)
      [his adventures in "taking charge of the western division of the New York & Erie rail-road," including his encounters with Philip Church of Belvedere]
    - 1834 July 10 (Box 1)
      [work and progress on the Western Division, a route over the dividing ridge, and the nature of his duties]
    - 1834 Aug 6 (Box 1)
      [the "immense extent of country to explore"; planned field work in Chautaugua County, New York]
    - 1834 Sep 9 (Box 1)
      [personal advice, refers to his idea to construct a bridge either over or below Niagara Falls and how wonderful the prospect sounds, especially to have one's name associated with such an endeavor; survey work and future plans for constructing and extending the line from the Hudson to the Mississippi and then to the Rocky Mountains (over 30 years); mentioning DeWitt Clinton's (1769-1828) previous work in the area [as canal commissioner?]
    - 1834 Dec 17 (Box 1)
      [re the death of his sister Mary and work in his division on surveying]
    - 1835 Apr 5 (Box 1)
      [considering offering himself as a candidate for the professorship of mathematics at South Carolina College at Columbia, mentioning Dr. [Robert] Adrain (1775-1843), and offering support]
    - 1835 June 23 (Box 1)
      [work in his Division, negotiations in Virginia and Illinois, capital backing for New York and Erie Road; a letter re his appointment on the James River canal as 'Division Engineer']
    - 1835 Aug 9 (Box 1)
      [Lynchburg, devoted to making an examination of his line and considering a plan for the construction of the work]
    - 1835 Oct 15 (Box 1)
      [Lynchburg, personal]
    - 1837 Mar 7 (Box 1)
      [Richmond, offers services as Consulting Engineer on a planned road project; importance of the Raleigh and Columbia road]
    - 1837 May 2 (Box 1)
      [Richmond, personal]
    - 1837 Oct 12 (Box 1)
      [re his impending marriage]
  - Alexander Yelverton Peyton Garnett (1819-1888) to Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett
    - 1841 Oct 9 (Box 1)
      [U. S. Sloop [of War] Cyane, feeling of isolation, medical tasks on board, [William Paul Crillon?] Barton (1786-1856), and awaiting orders to sail Pacific for three years]
    - 1842 Nov 14 (Box 1)
      [U. S. Ship Cyane, Bay of Monterey, refers to the American occupation of Monterey without authorization of the United States government; mentions [Thomas ap Catesby Jones], Commander-in-Chief of the U. S. Naval Forces on the Pacific; his dissatisfaction over the salaries of naval personnel and contempt for Congress and [John] Tyler]
    - 1844 Jan 13 (Box 1)
      [U. S. Ship Cyane, Bay of [Lan Blas?], giving personal advice; status of California and his beliefs that the U. S. Government should acquire the territory and describes environmental conditions; addendum: refers to missionary proceedings]
      [ see Journal of a Cruise to the Pacific Ocean, 1842-1844, in the Frigate United States, ed. Charles Roberts Anderson. G549.J6]
    - 1848 Dec 13 (Box 1)
      [Washington, D. C., re Garnett's political beginnings, politics, [Henry Alexander] Wise (1806-1876), Robert Mercer Taliaferro Hunter (1809-1887)]
    - 1849 Jan 17 (Box 1)
      [Washington, D. C., work on Garnett's standing as a candidate [for the Virginia Constitutional Convention]
    - 1849 June 29 (Box 1)
      [Bureau of MA Surgery, re Thomas Hart Benton's (1789-1871) attack on [John Caldwell] Calhoun (1782-1850) and the South; trying to get replies from [Henry Stuart] Foote (1804-1880) and [Henry A.] Wise (1806- 1876)]
    - 1850 Mar 31 (Box 1)
      [Washington, D. C., politics, Garnett's pamphlet "The Union...," Calhoun's death]
  - Charles Fenton Mercer Garnett (1810-1886) to Maria Hunter Garnett and Muscoe R. H. Garnett
    - 1830 Apr 23 (Box 1)
      [Mount Monococy, Maryland, re the burying grounds of the American Aborigines and finding Indian antiquities; describes area]
    - 1832 July 23 (Box 1)
      [Petersburg, Virginia, personal news]
    - 1842 May 4 (Box 1)
      [Milledgeville, Georgia, re problems with debts and unkind creditors]
    - 1845 May 26 (Box 1)
      [Marietta, Georgia, re his desire to return to Virginia, Georgia poliltics, Governor [George Washington] Crawford (1798-1872), and his dislike of Georgia]
    - 1848 Nov 5 (Box 1)
      [Murfreesboro, Tennessee, re politics, Whigs, [Lewis] Cass' (1782- 1866) Democratic nomination for U. S. President, his faith in the character of [Zachary] Taylor (1784-1850), thoughts on compromise bills, and the uncertainty of work as an engineer]
    - 1850 Dec 27 (Box 1)
      [Huntsville, Alabama, re his desire to be the architect of the grand national road from Memphis to the Chesapeake Bay, his admiration by locals, and his despondency over his personal life despite his career high]
    - 1856 July 12 (Box 1)
      [Ship Banshee, Chesapeake Bay, 15 miles from Old Point, to MHG, with news of the beginning of his journey]
    - 1856 Sep 7 (Box 1)
      [Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, to MHG, with description of Rio de Janeiro, activities of the Brisilian 4th of July, and conditions of climate and sea during the voyage. Mentions an invitation to dine on the U. S. Man of War Savannah and a ride to shore, the respectful treatment received, a plan to ride over the "contemplated line of road," the death of the Prime Minister, and the Marquis of Parana. Gives a description of the Emperor and being presented to him. Includes a travel chart with date, latitude, longitude, thermometer, and barometer readings]
    - [Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, to MHG, re being treated with kindness and distinction, meeting an interesting man by the name of George Rudge, and meeting Baron Mana] 1856 Sep 19 (Box 1)
    - 1856 Oct 26 (Box 1)
      [Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, mentions various food commodities (port wine, preserves, bananas, oranges, pineapples, cocoa nuts, and coffee), the damp climate, local social customs, lack of social life, friends and acquaintances, American government interests, flour import, coffee export, the scarcity of bread and bread substitutes, the language rules, the food of the negro slaves, and other foods (monkey, armadilla, snail). Also writes of beginning a grand expedition in the morning and inquires about coal lands]
    - [1856] (Box 1)
      [onboard (first four pages missing), re boredom at sea and admiration of sea life (porpoises, fish, dolphin), passing U. S. Alice, the civilities miles away from human habitat, and passing through the tropics]
    - 1858 Jan 14 (Box 1)
      [Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, re business affairs with R. H. Maury]
    - 1858 Jan 24 (Box 1)
      [Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, re business affairs with R. H. Maury, hiring an engineer for the Province of Rio Grande do Sul, social life being more active, friendships with naval officers, yellow fever, and a shipment of coffee to Baltimore by bark Sophia]
    - 1858 Jan 29 (Box 1)
      [Fazenda do Macaco (Province of Rio de Janeiro), re business affairs with R. H. Maury, the coffee shipment, and assistance with business matters]
    - 1858 Jan 29 (Box 1)
      [Fazenda do Macaco, Province of Rio de Janeiro, to MHG, re being homesick, being treated well by the Brazilians, government approval of his plans, the hot climate, social life and life in general]
    - 1858 Mar 16 (Box 1)
      [Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, re bout with yellow fever, the celebration for the opening of 32 miles of road, his assistant, Bernard F. Carter, nephew of Charles Carter Lee. Discusses business affairs, including mortgage, coal lands, and negroes (Bob, Henry, Tom, Dick, Betsey and children) and their sale of placement]
    - 1858 May 13 (Box 1)
      [Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, with business instructions including buying a farm for Florentina and selling negroes, and requesting a pamphlet on slavery to be written]
    - 1858 May 13 (Box 1)
      [Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, to MHG, re bout with yellow fever, plans for crossing the Serra do Mar and engineering and contractual difficulties, and having Nicolas Nello Carneiro Leao as a friend]
    - 1858 June 9 (Box 1)
      [Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, to MHG, re general news of the weather and his health and the "storm of abolition"]
    - 1858 July 7 (Box 1)
      [Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, re the coffee shipments and business instructions including stopping the sale of negroes, and a dentist from New York, Dr. Van Tuyl]
    - 1858 July 10 (Box 1)
      [Fazenda dos Macacos, Brazil, re disposition of his negroes and the coffee shipment]
    - 1858 July 20 (Box 1)
      [Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, to MHG, re making money in Brazil and his decision to stay four more years]
    - 1858 Sep 1 (Box 1)
      [Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, re business affairs and his disappointment in having no letters from the recipient]
    - 1858 Sep 6 (Box 1)
      [Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, re negotiating a new contract and planning a visit home in May of the following year]
    - 1858 Oct 21 (Box 1)
      [Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, re business affairs, negotiating a contract for five years, and his high standing with the government]
    - 1871 May 23 (Box 1)
      [personal news, gardening and raising chickens]
  - Eliza Lucinda Garnett (1815-1847) to James Mercer Garnett and Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett
    - n.d. (Box 1)
      [child's letter]
    - 1839 May 28 (Box 1)
      [Elmwood, to MRHG, re personal and family news]
    - n.y. Dec 4 (Box 1)
      [personal and family news and father going to Great National Humbug]
    - n.d. (Box 1)
      [personal and family news]
  - Grace Fenton Garnett (1779-1826) to family
    - 1793 Jan 22 (Box 1)
      [to "Dear cousin"]
    - 1796 Sep 20 (Box 1)
      [to [ ? ] re family news]
    - n.d. (Box 1)
      [to Maria Hunter re family news and an offer to swap [negroes] John for Elisha]
    - n.d. (Box 1)
      [to "Dear Mary" requesting an encyclopedia entry about the mumps]
    - n.d. (Box 1)
      [to "Dear Molly" re personal and family news (5 letters)]
    - n.d. (Box 1)
      [to "My dear Sister" re family news]
  - James Mercer Garnett (1770-1843) to Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett
    - [Richmond, re personal news] 1829 Nov 18 (Box 1)
    - 1833 July 17 (Box 1)
      [Richmond, re personal news]
    - 1833 Sep 17 (Box 1)
      [Elmwood, with instructions for Mr. Norris the blacksmith and certain requests]
    - 1833 Sep (Box 1)
      [Elmwood, re the school opening the following week]
    - [1837] (Box 1)
      [Elmwood, with instructions for Mr. Stregel's models]
    - 1838 Oct 6 (Box 1)
      [Fredericksburg, to MRHG at the University of Virginia, with discussion and advice on education, matters of conduct and moral courage]
    - 1841 Oct 17 (Box 1)
      [to MRHG at the University of Virginia, discussing the study of law as indispensable to being a great and honest statesman]
    - Thursday evening (Box 1)
    - Sunday evening (Box 1)
  - James Mercer Garnett, Jr. (1794-1824) to Maria (Hunter) Garnett
    - 1820 July 25 (Box 1)
      [Port Royal to West River, Maryland, re personal and family news]
    - 1823 Sep 22 (Box 1)
      [Fredericksburg to Elmwood, re personal news]
    - 1824 Apr 21 (Box 1)
    - 1824 Apr 25 (Box 1)
    - 1824 Apr 27 (Box 1)
      [Fredericksburg to Elmwood, with supportive and uplifting words, advice on son Muscoe, and personal news]
    - 1824 Apr 30 (Box 1)
    - 1824 (Box 1)
      [resolution in memory of James Mercer Garnett, Jr.]
  - James Mercer Garnett, Jr. (1794-1824) to James Mercer and Mary Eleanor Dick (Mercer) Garnett
    - 1811 Nov 11 (Box 1)
      [Georgetown to Mother, Pittsville, Essex County, mentioning Mr. Randolph [John Randolph of Roanoke (1773-1833) ? ] at the Capitol; describing Congress Hall and Senate Chamber; and mentioning cousin John Taliaferro (1768-1852)
    - 1811 Nov 20 (Box 1)
      [St. Mary's College to Father, Pittsville, Essex County, re college life]
    - 1811 Nov 23 (Box 1)
      [St. Mary's College, Baltimore, Maryland, to Mother, Pittsville, Essex County, re college life]
  - James "Mercer" Garnett (1861-1908) to Maria (Hunter) Garnett
    - 1869 Mar 23, July 30 (Box 1)
      [Castle Point]
    - 1870 Jan 20, Feb 19, Mar 7, June 21 (Box 1)
      [Pau, France]
    - 1870 Aug 4 (Box 1)
      [Geneva, Switzerland, re travels around area]
    - 1870 Aug 13 (Box 1)
      [Bern, Switzerland, re travels around area]
    - 1870 Oct 13 (Box 1)
      [Venice, Italy, re visits to Lucerne and Lugano, Switzerland, and Como, Milan, and Venice, Italy]
    - 1870 Nov 19, Dec 3 (Box 1)
      [Vevey, Switzerland, re sight seeing around area and mentioning the French/Prussian conflict]
    - 1870 Dec 26 (Box 1)
      [Rome, Italy, re the death of "Julie"]
    - 1871 Feb 12 (Box 1)
      [Naples, Italy, mentioning a visit to Sorrento and Pompeii, Italy, and sightseeing on the way to Baiae]
    - 1871 Feb 28 (Box 1)
      [Rome, Italy, re carnival in town--description, visits to Villa Pamphille Doria, Appian Way, the Campagnato to the Via, Latina around Rome]
    - 1871 Mar 18 (Box 1)
      [Rome, Italy, re sightseeing trip to Ostia, Italy, a celebration re the birthday of Prince Humbert, and a visit to Temple of Minerva]
    - 1871 Mar 28 (Box 1)
      [Rome, Italy, mentioning "great illumination here at Easter"]
    - 1871 Apr 29 (Box 1)
      [Geneva, Switzerland, going to school in the Chateau de Lancy]
    - 1871 June 8 (Box 1)
      [Geneva, Switzerland, re school]
    - 1871 Nov 12 (Box 1)
      [Geneva, Switzerland, re mother's plan to spend winter in Nice, France, and skating in Switzerland]
    - 1871 Dec 27 (Box 1)
      [Nice, France, re holidays]
    - 1872 Jan 12 (Box 1)
      [Chateau de Lancy, Switzerland, personal; with letter, from Minnie, personal]
    - 1872 July 3 (Box 1)
      [Geneva, Switzerland, re mother's liver ailment, school grades, and a General Rhett now in the Egyptian army]
    - 1872 July 21 (Box 1)
      [Geneva, Switzerland, personal]
    - 1872 Sep 23 (Box 1)
      [Chateau de Lancy, Switzerland, re school and an excursion to Vevey]
    - 1873 Jan 5 (Box 1)
      [Paris, France, re the holidays in Paris and activities while there]
  - John Mercer Garnett (1783-1856) to family
    - 1793 Aug 16 (Box 1)
      [to sister, personal, mentioning novel Celestina[by Charlotte Turner Smith (1749-1806), 1791]
    - 1825 Jan 3 (Box 1)
      [promissory note to Grace F. Hunter for hire of "a negro man named Wyatt']
  - Maria (Hunter) Garnett (1797-1873) to Mary Picton (Stevens) Garnett
    - 1865 [Jan 1] (Box 1)
      [refers to the death of her son and Mary's husband, Muscoe in 1864, and her grief, the necessity of Mary and the children returning home, personal and family news; with letter to Mercer]
    - 1865 Feb 9 (Box 1)
    - 1865 Mar 2 (Box 1)
    - 1865 Aug 7 (Box 1)
      [re after-effects of North/South confrontation, legislature passed, and related activities; the children's property, personal and family news; with letter to Mercer, mentioning "Uncle Robert" being in a prison]
    - 1866 Feb 22 (Box 1)
      [re their financial matters; with letter to Mercer]
    - 1867 May 3 (Box 1)
      [wanting Muscoe's children nearby; with letter to Mercer and Minnie]
    - 1868 Oct 13 (Box 1)
      [personal news]
    - n.y. Feb 10 (Box 1)
      [to grandchild]
    - n.y. Feb 13 [1865?] (Box 1)
      [re broken heart and spirit over not seeing her grandchildren]
    - n.y. Feb 12 [1866?] (Box 1)
      [re their financial matters, effects of the war on these matters, including property and problems with negro labor; with letter to Mercer]
    - n.y. Mar 6 [1866?] (Box 1)
      [personal and family news, "small business" details; with letter to Mercer]
    - n.y. Mar 13 (Box 1)
      [to Mercer]
    - n.y. Mar 29 (Box 1)
      [re financial matters, personal and family news]
    - n.y. Apr 6 (Box 1)
      [re effects after war, Freedmen's Bureau, and blacks]
    - n.y. July 1 (Box 1)
      [re children visiting, with letter from Mercer and Minnie to their mother]
    - n.y. Aug 4 (Box 1)
      [personal and family news, financial matters]
    - n.y. Aug 30 (Box 1)
      [personal and family news, requests certain goods; Mercer visiting]
    - n.y. Sep 2 (Box 1)
      [financial matters; Mercer visiting]
    - n.y. Sep 6 (Box 1)
      [personal and family news; Mercer visiting]
    - n.y. Sep 12 (Box 1)
      [re financial matters; Mercer visiting; with letter from Robert Baylor re Mr. Capron's account]
    - n.y. Sep 29 (Box 1)
    - n.y. Oct 1 (Box 1)
      [wishing to hear from her, personal health and news]
    - n.y. Oct 2 (Box 1)
      [personal and family news; with letter to Mercer]
    - (Box 1)
    - [mentions chills and fever among servants at "Elmwood"; Mercer visiting] n.y. Oct 9 (Box 1)
    - n.y. Oct 10 (Box 1)
      [personal and family news and clothing]
    - n.y. Oct 18 (Box 1)
    - n.y. Oct 19 (Box 1)
    - n.y. Oct 26 (Box 1)
      [personal]
    - n.y. Oct 30 (Box 1)
      [personal and family news and Mercer's education]
    - n.y. Nov 2 (Box 1)
      [personal and family news, financial matters including Joe Gouldman, the sale of Mt. Pleasant, Virginia, and West Virginia properties]
    - n.y. Nov 2 (Box 1)
      [to Mercer, personal and family news and his schooling]
    - n.y. Nov 6 (Box 1)
      [asking their plans for the winter]
    - n.y. Nov 9 (Box 1)
      [re financial matters and problems with Muscoe's estate and the "Elmwood" property]
    - n.y. Nov 10 (Box 1)
    - n.y. Nov 14 (Box 1)
      [re financial matters and inquiring about winter plans]
    - n.y. Nov 17 (Box 1)
      [personal and family news; re financial matters including the estate, Kanawha mine in suit, and coal property]
    - n.y. Nov 23 (Box 1)
      [personal and family news; re financial matters concerning the coal property]
    - n.y. Nov 25 (Box 1)
      [personal and family news; re financial matters]
    - n.y. Dec 14 (Box 1)
    - n.y. Dec 21 (Box 1)
      [personal and family news; re financial matters and an incident happening to Mary]
    - n.d. (Box 1)
      [to "My own dear Grandson"]
    - n.d. (Box 1)
      [to "My own little darling," re Christmas spirit]
    - n.d. (Box 1)
      [to "My dear Mary," personal and family news]
    - n.d. (Box 1)
      [to "My dear daughter," news of Mercer and Minnie, and Mary's sickness]
    - n.d. (Box 1)
      [to "Dr Mary," re church hangings/carpet]
    - n.d. (Box 1)
      [to "My dear Mary," re coal property; personal and fmaily news]
    - (Box 1)
    - n.d. (Box 1)
      [to "My dear Mary," personal and family news; with letter to "My darling little Mercer"]
    - n.d. (Box 1)
    - n.d. (Box 1)
      [financial statement]
  - Maria (Hunter) Garnett (1797-1873) to Muscoe Russell Hunter Garnett
    [These letters are full of personal and family news, in addition to the other topics mentioned]
    - 1838 Feb 11 (Box 1)
      [to UVa, family debts and hardships of being in debt, abolition]
    - 1838 Mar 9 (Box 1)
      [to UVa, motherly support and advice]
    - 1838 May 25 (Box 1)
      [to UVa, concern over his health, local elections and politics]
    - 1838 June 28 (Box 1)
      [to UVa, following a visit during his ill health, the trip to Junction, Virginia]
    - 1838 Sep 27 (Box 1)
      [to UVa, concern for his health]
    - 1838 Sep 30 (Box 1)
      [to UVa, concern for his happiness and health, religious support, and advice on his education]
    - 1838 Oct 1 (Box 1)
      [to UVa]
    - 1838 Oct 2 (Box 1)
      [to UVa, concern for his health and happiness]
    - 1838 Oct 4 (Box 1)
      [to UVa, encouragement for his success, school reading materials]
    - 1838 Oct 8 (Box 1)
      [to UVa, religious support]
    - 1838 Oct 11 (Box 1)
      [to UVa, his uncle's [R. M. T. Hunter] political stand and reactions by the people, concern over health, happiness, and education]